No way.
（椿）嘘。　この前　お見舞い
行ったとき　普通に話したよ。→
When I went to see her the other day, we talked like always.
今度　一緒に
春服　買いに行こうって。
We even made plans to go shopping for spring clothes together.
（渡）俺と　公生が　病院に行ったら
急にさ…。
When Kousei and I got to the hospital...
It all happened so fast.
（渡）かをりちゃん　今
集中治療室に入ってる。
Kaori's in the ICU right now.
She's gonna be okay, right?
大丈夫なんだよね？
また会えるんだよね？
We can see her again, right?
分からない。
けど　相当よくないみたいだ。
I dunno.
But it really didn't look good for her.
（柏木）そんな…。
No...
（椿）「俺と　公生が」って
公生も知ってるの？
You and Kousei?
So Kousei knows about this too?
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
TKGSETO HIROKOBCV
SETO HIROKO
END CALL
Arima
（椿）《お願い。
公生を助けてください》→
Arima
Please...
Save Kousei, please...
《公生が　また駄目になっちゃう》
Kousei's going to fall apart again...
END CALL
Arima
Call Ended
（紘子）ハァ…。
Arima
Call Ended
（紘子）ゴラー！　公生！
入るよ！
Damn it, Kousei!
I'm coming in!
（紘子）公生！　あっ…。
Kousei!
（紘子）何やってんの！？
状況　分かってんの？　あんた！→
What do you think you're doing?
Do you understand the situation you're in?
The competition is coming up soon!
コンクールまで
もう何日もないのよ！
練習するわよ！
さっさと　立ちな！
Okay, we're going to practice!
Get on your feet right now!
（公生）無理です…。
I can't do this...
もう無理。
I can't do this anymore...
紘子さん。
どうして　こうなっちゃうの。
Hiroko,
why does it have to end up this way?
《僕は　僕は　ただ…》
All I ever wanted was...
《ピアノを弾いて→
to play the piano, and make my mother get well. Nothing more.
お母さんに　元気になって
ほしかっただけなのに》
All I did...
《僕は　ただ
恋をしただけなのに…》
was fall in love.
Why... does it have to end up this way?
どうして　こうなっちゃうの。
もう　無理です。
I can't... go on.
もう　頑張れないよ。
No more...
I can't try anymore...
STOP
Requested.
Watari
（かをり）
《カワイイ　レターセット！》
This stationery is adorable!
Requested.
Watari
I want caneles.
Medication Room
やあ。
Hey!
昨日ね　病室に戻ってこれたの。
They let me come back to my room yesterday.
いやあ　参った。
Man, what an ordeal.
集中治療室なんて
初めて入ったよ。
That was my first time ever inside an ICU.
落ち着かないね　あそこ。
You just can't relax in there, you know.
恥ずかしいとこ
見られちゃったな。
You really caught me at an awkward moment!
だから　病院に来るなって
言ったのに。
That's why I told you not to come to the hospital.
チョー！
Hey!
（公生）あうっ！　な…　何を…。
Wh-What are you doing?
Don't come to see me and then
stand around looking so gloomy!
お見舞いに来て
辛気くさい面してんじゃねぇ！
ええっ。
余計　具合が悪くなるわ！
You're gonna make me even sicker!
あっ。　カヌレ。　外で食べたい。
Oh...
Canelés! I want to eat them outside!
It's too cold.
寒いよ。
病室は嫌。
But I don't wanna eat them here.
Come on, come on, come on!
ほれ　ほれ　ほれ　ほれ。
重いとか言ったら
ぶっ飛ばすかんね。
One word about me being heavy, and I'll kick your butt, got it?
フッ…。
もっと食べてもいいくらいだ。
I think you could stand to eat more.
She's light. So very light.
《軽い…。　とても》
《どこかで安心してた》
On some level, I felt at ease.
《もう平気なんだって》
That she was all right now.
That she was so strong, she could just send her illness packing.
《病気なんて蹴散らしちゃう
強い人なんだって》
《今が　ずっと続くんだって》
That this "now" would go on forever.
《縫いぐるみが好きで
甘い物が好き》
She loves stuffed animals and sweets.
《か弱い
君は普通の女の子なのに》
So fragile.
You're just a normal girl, and yet...
《僕はバカだ》
I'm a moron.
わあ…。
Wow...
雪だ。
Snow.
ピアノ　弾いてる？
Have you been practicing?
弾いてない。
I haven't.
やっぱり。
君は　いじけてる。
I knew it.
"You're feeling sorry for yourself."
もう　無理だ。
I can't do it anymore.
《大切な人は
僕の前から　去っていく》
The people I care about keep leaving me.
《音楽は
大切な人を　連れ去っていく》
Music takes the people I care about away from me.
《僕は　独りぼっちになる》
I'm going to be left all alone.
私がいるじゃん。
You have me.
私ね　手術するの。　２月１８日。
I'm going to have surgery, see.
Training with
Hiroko
Complete
Eastern Japan Piano
Competition
FINALS
On February 18.
私は必死にあがくよ。
I'm going to struggle as hard as I can.
I'm going to continue struggling like there's no tomorrow!
あがいて　あがいて
あがきまくってやる。
君のせい。
全部　全部　君のせい。
It's because of you.
It's all because of you.
《私がぶざまに　あがくのも→
The reason I'm putting up such an unseemly struggle,
生きることに執着するのも
君のせい》
the reason why I'm so fixated on living...
It's because of you.
《君が私に
君といる時間への未練をくれた》
You gave me
this desire to cling to the time that I spend with you.
君は　あがかないの？
私たち　あがくの得意じゃない。
Aren't you going to struggle too?
We're so good at struggling!
私たちは　命懸けであがく
演奏家じゃない。
We risk our lives to struggle because we're musicians, remember?
でも…。
But...
もう　１週間も
ピアノに触ってない。　指が…。
I haven't touched the piano for a week now. My fingers...
私の伴奏のときだって
そうだった。
It was the same when you were my accompanist.
Back then, I was always playing the piano for my part-time job.
あのときは　バイトで
いつもピアノに触ってた。
まともに弾けるわけない。
No way can I play decently now!
こんな状態で弾けたら　奇跡だ。
Being able to play in this state would be a miracle.
また　下　向いてる。
You're looking down again.
ほら　奇跡なんて
すぐ起こっちゃう。
See?
Miracles can happen!
ハハ…。　私の中に　君がいるよ。
You exist inside me,
有馬　公生君。
Arima Kousei.
卵サンドが好き。
モーモー印の牛乳が好き。
You like egg sandwiches.
You like Moo Moo Brand milk.
あと　何が好き？
好きな昆虫は？
What else do you like?
What are your favorite insects?
何を集めてた？
好きだったアニメは？
What kind of stuff did you collect?
What anime did you like?
There's so much that I don't know.
知らないこと　たくさんある。
何でも知ってる椿ちゃんが
うらやましい。
I envy Tsubaki for knowing everything.
I want to know so many things about you.
君のこと　たくさん知りたい。
怖いよ…。
So...
怖いよ…　怖いよ…。
I'm so scared.
Don't leave me all alone!
私を　一人にしないで。
《僕は　バカだ》
I'm a moron.
《暴力上等。　性格最低。
印象最悪》
She's ultra-violent.
Her personality blows.
She leaves the worst impression.
《でも　彼女は美しい》
But...
she's beautiful.
You're so beautiful in the snow.
《雪の中の君は　美しい》
Eastern Japan Piano Competition
Sponsored by Kanto Classical Music Assocation
（医師）麻酔　始めますね。
Eastern Japan Piano Competition
Sponsored by Kanto Classical Music Assocation
We're going to start the anesthesia, all right?
Eastern Japan Piano Competition
Sponsored by Kanto Classical Music Assocation
（医師）深呼吸して。
Now take a deep breath.
《「ねえ　先生　私たち　みんな→
Listen, Doctor...
"We all need someone to kiss us goodbye."
さよならのキスをしてくれる人が
要るんです」　マーシー》
OPERATION IN PROGRESS
Your Lie in April
Marcie.
（看護師）脈拍　安定しています。
Her pulse is stable.
（看護師）麻酔　完了しました。
The anesthesia induction is complete.
We're going to begin the surgery now.
（医師）手術を始めます。
Bravo!
（観客）ブラボー！
（観客）井川さーん！
Igawa!
Perfect... You couldn't have played better, Emi!
（落合）《取った…。
最高の出来よ。　絵見》
（凪）
《は～　ため息しか出ない》→
All I can do is sigh...
My brother gave a great performance too, but she was
on another level and didn't even concede an inch!
《お兄ちゃんも
会心の演奏だったけど→
別ベクトルで
一歩も引けを取らない》→
《そっか。
私の進む先に　この人がいるのか》
I see. So this person is ahead of
me on the path I want to follow.
（高柳）《見事だ》→
That was splendid.
I thought that Takeshi would be the
runaway favorite, but there's no way to tell.
《武士が断トツだと思ったが
甲乙つけがたい》→
《あとは　心証の差でしかない》
Artistic impression's all that separates them now.
You're certainly adding the finishing touches, you damn witch.
（高柳）
《仕上げてきたな。　魔女め》
This district is unbelievable.
この地区は　すごいね。
There are actually two prodigies.
２人も　天才がいる。
優勝はどっちかな？
Wonder which one's gonna win?
Oh, amateurs!
（三池）フッ　これだから素人は。
（三池）この後　最高のピアニストが控えてますから。
The greatest pianist of all has yet to play, you know.
Isn't that Miike?
（さつき）あれ？　三池。
（小麦）あっ。
Ms. Ochiai is always so adept at
fanning the flames of determination.
（紘子）相変わらず
人の執念をあおるのが上手ね。→
落合先生。
Ms. Seto, how was Arima?
（凪）瀬戸先生。
どうでしたか？　有馬先生。
Just awful.
（紘子）最悪だわ。
I brought him to the venue,
but who knows if he can play decently.
会場に連れてきたものの
まともに弾けるかどうか。
He's reverted to that state from two years ago.
２年前に逆戻り。
（紘子）
《コンクールの結果どころか→
It's not even a matter of how he does in this competition
anymore. He might very well be finished as a pianist too.
ピアニストとしても
駄目になるかもしれない》
《助けてよ　助けて　助けてよ》
Help me. Help me. Help me!
（紘子）こりゃあ　参ったね。
I'm at my wits' end...
Good job!
（実行委員）お疲れ。
（実行委員）よかったよ。
You were good!
（絵見）《見たか　武士。　有馬》
Did you see that, Takeshi? Arima?
（武士）おい　どうしたよ？
具合　悪いのか？
Hey, what's the matter?
You're not feeling well?
（武士）薬もらってこようか？
胃薬なら　すぐ持ってくるぞ。
Want me to get you some medicine?
I can bring you an antacid right away.
（絵見）集中してるんじゃないの？
Isn't he just getting himself focused?
あっ　ああ…。　でも　何か…。
Huh? Oh...
Yeah, but still...
...play.
弾かなきゃ。
（絵見）あっ…。
弾かなきゃ
弾かなきゃ　弾かなきゃ。
Gotta play, gotta play, gotta play.
OPERATION IN PROGRESS
Arima will be up soon.
（観客）《もうすぐ有馬だ》
（観客）《有馬だ》
Arima!
（観客）《有馬君が来る》
Arima's going to perform.
I can't wait!
（観客）《楽しみだ》
（観客）《生まれ変わった天才が》
To hear the transformed genius!
（実行委員）
２３番　有馬　公生君。
No. 23, Mr. Arima Kousei.
もうすぐ　出番です。
袖に来て　準備お願いします。
You're going on soon.
Please stand by in the wings.
H-Hey, are you okay?
（武士）お…　おい。　大丈夫か？
Yeah... I'm fine.
うん。　大丈夫。　大丈夫だから。
I'll be fine.
You're fine? Your face couldn't be paler.
（絵見）
大丈夫って…。　顔が真っ青だよ。→
Anybody can see that you're not yourself.
誰が見たって　普通じゃない。
一緒に医務室に行こうよ！
Come on, let's go to the infirmary!
Sorry.
ごめん。　でも　弾かなきゃ。
But... I have to play.
僕は　ピアニストだから。
Because I'm a pianist.
約束だから。
Because I promised.
（観客）《有馬だ》
（観客）《有馬君だ》
It's Arima!
Arima!
（三池）《来た！　有馬さん！》
There he is! It's Arima!
あいつ　ぶっ倒れたりしねえよな？
He's not gonna pass out or anything, is he?
《思い出したくないこと
思い出させちゃったね》
I'm making you remember something that you don't want to.
《弓を持てないバイオリニストなんて
意味ないもの》
There's no point if the violinist can't even hold her own bow.
《私　忘れない。
死んでも忘れない》
I won't forget.
I won't forget, even if I die.
《弾かなきゃ》
I have to play.
《忘れちゃえばいいんだよ。
リセットボタンを押すみたいに》
Just forget about it all, like you pressed the reset button.
《弾かなきゃ》
《こんななら→
I have to play.
It might've been better if we never met, huh?
My Sweet Accomplice     Mita Masahiro
会わなきゃよかったね》
I have to play.
《弾かなきゃ　弾かなきゃ。
僕は　ピアニストだから》
I have to play.
Because... I'm a pianist.
先生？
（紘子）公生…！
Arima?
Kousei!
（観客）どうした？
（観客）プレッシャー？
What's going on?
Is it the pressure?
（観客）有馬が？
It's getting to Arima?
《また　下　向いてる》
You're looking down again.
（柏木）《バカ椿》
（渡）《他人のふり　他人のふり》
Tsubaki, you dummy!
I don't know you! I don't know you!
《椿…　来てるんだ。　そうか》
Tsubaki...
You're here...
I see.
《みんな　見てるんだ》
Everybody's... watching me.
（絵見）
《単なるペザンテじゃない》
This isn't just pesante.
（武士）
《深く　ゆったりした響き》
It sounds so deep, so unhurried.
（高柳）《ああ…
なんて豊かな音色なんだ》
Ah... What a remarkably rich sound.
（紘子）《ショパン
『バラード第１番　ト短調　作品２３』》
Chopin's Ballade No. 1 in G Minor, Op. 23.
（落合）《ささやくように
甘えるように　優しく悲しげに→
Like a whisper, like a show of affection, so gently...
ショパンのバラードが
奏でられていく》
The sound of Chopin's Ballade, emanating so sorrowfully.
You were thinking about a girl you like, weren't you?
（渡）《好きな子のこと
考えてたろ？》
《そりゃ　そうさ》
Of course I was.
（紘子）《今は　心のままに
弾きなさい》
Play like your heart desires.
《心の中は　カオスです》
But my heart's a mess.
（凪）《陳腐です》
What a cliché.
《ちょっとは
いいこと言ってるよ》
It's not all bad, you know.
（椿）《何よ。　さっきから
ピアノばっか弾いて！》
What's wrong with you? All you're doing is playing the piano!
I can't help it. I was never good with words.
《仕方ないだろ。
口下手なんだから》
《みんな　見てる》
Everybody's watching.
《僕が　今　ここにいるのは
みんながいたからだ》
The reason I'm here right now is because I had you.
《僕の人生に関わった人》
The people who played a part in my life.
《僕を豊かにしてくれた人》
The people who made my life fuller.
《僕は応えなきゃ》
I can't let them down.
（武士）《俺ら　演奏家だからよ。
物は音楽で語らねえとな》
It's probably because we're musicians.
So everything's gotta be expressed in music, right?
《ああ　相座。　そのとおりだ》
Yeah, Aiza.
You're absolutely right.
《悲しくても　ボロボロでも→
Whether you're sad, you're a mess, or you've hit rock bottom, you still have to play!
どん底にいても
弾かなきゃ駄目なの！》
《僕にできるかな？》
Do you think I can do it?
《平気　平気。　何とかなるって！
私たち　最強だもん》
No worries, we'll figure it out!
'Cause we rule!
《弾くんだ　弾くんだ》
I'll keep playing.
That's who I am, how I'm going to live my life.
《僕は　そうやって
生きていく人種なんだ》
《僕はピアニストなんだから》
Because I'm a pianist.
《君と同じ　演奏家なんだから》
Just like you...
I'm a musician, after all!
（三池）《すごい…！》
Amazing!
This is incredible, Arima!
（凪）《すごいよ　有馬先生》→
《先生の人生は　先生の音楽は→
Your life, your music...
こんなにも
カラフルに色付いている》
It's taken on all this color!
（紘子）《公生の演奏は
カラフルに色付いている》→
Kousei's performance is bursting with color.
Episode 21
Snow
Bursting with such mournful color.
《悲しげに　色付いている》
Final Episode
Spring Breeze
sore zore no yume wo erande
No two dreams can be the same
Final Episode
Spring Breeze
sore zore no yume wo erande
No two dreams can be the same
Watch next week too!